Mathias Thor - Curriculum Vitae

Danish • Born March 21 - 1993 • GSM +45 2918 4320 • Web mathiasthor.github.io • Mail mathias_thor@hotmail.com

Summery

Mathias Thor is currently pursuing a PhD degree with SDU Embodied Systems for Robotics and Learning at the University of Southern Denmark. The primary aim of his research is to develop adaptive locomotion controllers that are able to recognize and adapt to different robot bodies and environments. Although in his early years of conducting research, Mathias has already won several awards, been granted the EliteForsk travel grant, and published many scientific papers on artificial intelligence and robotics.



Education

2017 - 2021 4+4 Ph.D., University Of Southern Denmark [mathias@mmmi.sdu.dk]

Project title: Neurorobotic Technology for Advanced Robot Motor Control

Supervisor: Poramate Manoonpong

2016 - 2019 Master of Science in Robotics, University Of Southern Denmark

Danish weighted average master grade average of 12.0 (w/o mater thesis)

Project title: Modular Legged-Robotic System

Supervisor: Poramate Manoonpong

Master thesis grade: 12

2013 - 2016 Bachelor of Science in Robotics, University Of Southern Denmark

Danish weighted average bachelor grade average of 10.9 (w/o bachelor thesis)

Project title: Embodied control of a dung beetle inspired hexapod

Supervisor: Poramate Manoonpong

Bachelor thesis grade: 12

Experience

2019 - 2020 Co-supervising two master students

40*2 ECTS - 10-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark

- 2019 Guest talk on Robotics, Neural Control and Reinforcement Learning BRAIN-LAB Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology, Thailand
- 2019 Teaching "Adaptive embodied locomotion control systems" 5*2 ECTS - 9-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Teaching "Adaptive embodied locomotion control systems" 5*2 ECTS 9-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Co-supervising two master students 15*2 ECTS - 6-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark
- 2018 Co-supervising two bachelor students
 30*2 ECTS 10-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark

| 2018 | Teaching the course "Underactuated Robotics" 5 ECTS - 6-semester Robot Systems, University of Southern Denmark |
|-------------|---|
| 2017 - 2018 | Teaching assistant on the course "Mathematical methods in programming" 5 ECTS - 1-semester Physics and Technology, University of Southern Denmark |
| 2015 - 2017 | Student programmer at Universal Robots Odense, Denmark |

Conference contributions

| 2019 | Presenting a paper at the iROS2019 conference The Venetian, Macau |
|------|--|
| 2018 | Media Operation and session Chair at the IYCBE2018 conference University of Southern Denmark |
| 2018 | Presenting a paper at the IYCBE2018 conference University of Southern Denmark |
| 2017 | Presenting a paper at the SWARM2017 conference Kyoto University, Japan |

Publication list

2020

Generic Neural Locomotion Control Framework for Legged Robots

M. Thor, T. Kulvicius, and P. Manoonpong

IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems 2020 (Journal paper - under review)

2019

A Fast Online Frequency Adaptation Mechanism for CPG-Based Robot Motion Control

M. Thor, and P. Manoonpong

IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters 2019 (Journal paper)

Error-Based Learning Mechanism for Fast Online Adaptation in Robot Motor Control

M. Thor, and P. Manoonpong

IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems 2019 (Journal paper)

CPG Driven RBF Network Control with Reinforcement Learning for Gait Optimization of a Dung Beetle-Like Robot

Matheshwaran Pitchai, Xiaofeng Xiong, <u>Mathias Thor</u>, Peter Billeschou, Peter Lukas Mailänder, Binggwong Leung, Tomas Kulvicius, and Poramate Manoonpong

In Artificial Neural Networks and Machine Learning – ICANN 2019: Theoretical Neural Computation (Conference paper)

Modular Neural Control for Dung Beetle-like Leg Movements of a Dung Beetle-like Robot

Binggwong Leung, Mathias Thor, and Poramate Manoonpong

In the 9th International Symposium on Adaptive Motion of Animals and Machines (Conference paper)

2018

MORF - Modular Robot Framework

Mathias Thor, Jørgen Christian Larsen, and Poramate Manoonpong

In The 2nd International Youth Conference of Bionic Engineering - IYCBE2018 (Conference paper)

- Best Student Paper Award

A dung beetle-inspired robotic model and its distributed sensor-driven control for walking and ball rolling

M. Thor, T. Strøm-Hansen, L. B. Larsen, A. Kovalev, S. N. Gorb, E. Baird, and P. Manoonpong *Artificial Life and Robotics 2018 (Journal paper)*

Modular neural control for bio-inspired walking and ball rolling of a dung beetle-like robot

Binggwong Leung, <u>Mathias Thor</u>, and Poramate Manoonpong *In ALife 2018 (Conference paper)*

2017

Advantages of using a biologically plausible embodied kinematic model for enhancement of speed and multifunctionality of a walking robot

Mathias Thor, Theis Strøm-Hansen, and Leon Bonde Larsen

In Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium on Swarm Behavior and Bio-Inspired Robotics - SWARM2017 (Conference paper)

- Best Student Paper Award

Distributed Sensor-Driven Control for Bio-Inspired Walking and Ball Rolling of a Dung Beetle-Like Robot

Theis Strøm-Hansen, <u>Mathias Thor</u>, Leon Bonde Larsen, Emily Baird, and Poramate Manoonpong In Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium on Swarm Behavior and Bio-Inspired Robotics - SWARM2017 (Conference paper)

Fundings

EliteForsk-Travel Grant 2019

Funding Agency: Ministry of Education and Research (Copenhagen)

Amount: DKK 200.000
Grant period: 2019-01 to 2020-12

Foundation Idella Study Travel Grant 2018

Funding Agency: Ministry of Education and Research (Copenhagen)

Amount: DKK 20.000

Grant period: 2018-08 to 2019-06

International partners

Zhendong Dai: Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, China. Collaboration on robot control and bio-inspired movement.

Stanislav Gorb: Kiel University, Germany. Collaboration on the modelling of insects and their movement.

Emily Baird: Lund University, Sweden. Collaboration on the modelling of insects and their movement.

BRAIN-LAB: Vidyasirimedhi Institute of Science and Technology, Thailand. Collaboration on Locomotion control and robot design.